[
    {
        "question": "Where is the olfactory epithelium located?",
        "a": "surrounding the tongue",
        "b": "covering the surface of the lungs",
        "c": "lining the top and the back of the nasal cavity",
        "d": "coating the bottom of the nasal cavity",
        "e": "encasing the olfactory bulb",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the main components of the olfactory epithelium?",
        "a": "olfactory receptors and taste buds",
        "b": "support cells and taste buds",
        "c": "olfactory receptors and blood vessels",
        "d": "basal cells and support cells",
        "e": "basal cells and blood vessels",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do olfactory receptor neurons transduce odor stimuli?",
        "a": "by producing odorant molecules",
        "b": "by secreting mucus",
        "c": "by activating taste receptors",
        "d": "by releasing neurotransmitters",
        "e": "by generating electrical signals",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are the receptors for smell particles or odorants located?",
        "a": "nasal epithelium",
        "b": "sensory epithelium",
        "c": "olfactory bulb",
        "d": "mucus layer",
        "e": "sinus cavity",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do odorants reach the olfactory receptors in the nasal cavity?",
        "a": "They pass through the blood-brain barrier to reach the receptors.",
        "b": "They dissolve in the mucus layer of the olfactory epithelium.",
        "c": "They travel to the olfactory bulb.",
        "d": "They are transduced in the nasal epithelium.",
        "e": "They directly bind to the olfactory receptors.",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mammals have the largest known gene family encoding for odorant receptors?",
        "a": "primates",
        "b": "rodents",
        "c": "bats",
        "d": "felines",
        "e": "canines",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which G protein is involved in olfactory receptor neuron signaling?",
        "a": "G protein for Olfaction (Golf)",
        "b": "G protein-coupled receptors (GPCR)",
        "c": "G-protein receptor",
        "d": "adenylyl cyclase",
        "e": "cyclic adenosine monophosphate (cAMP)",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which second messenger does adenylyl cyclase produce in olfactory receptor neurons?",
        "a": "calcium",
        "b": "ATP",
        "c": "G protein",
        "d": "cyclic adenosine monophosphate (cAMP)",
        "e": "chloride",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the depolarization of olfactory receptor neurons occur?",
        "a": "Chloride ions flow out of the cell.",
        "b": "Sodium and calcium ions flow out of the cell.",
        "c": "Sodium and calcium ions flow into the cell.",
        "d": "Potassium ions flow into the cell.",
        "e": "Chloride ions flow into the cell.",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which structures in the olfactory bulb serve as the termination points for olfactory receptor axons?",
        "a": "granule cells",
        "b": "cribriform plates",
        "c": "periventricular cells",
        "d": "mitral cells",
        "e": "glomeruli",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cranial nerve transmits olfactory signals from the olfactory bulb to the brain?",
        "a": "cranial nerve four",
        "b": "cranial nerve three",
        "c": "cranial nerve five",
        "d": "cranial nerve two",
        "e": "cranial nerve one",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the role of the hippocampus in olfactory processing?",
        "a": "localization of odor information",
        "b": "perception of smell intensity",
        "c": "memory related to smells",
        "d": "emotional response to smells",
        "e": "generation of action potentials",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "In taste perception, each axon carrying information to the brain",
        "a": "represents a single-taste cell",
        "b": "is specific to one type of flavor",
        "c": "brings information from multiple taste cells",
        "d": "mixes taste and smell information",
        "e": "responds differently to different tastes",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is the mixing of taste information helpful?",
        "a": "It prevents the loss of taste sensation.",
        "b": "It provides a clearer perception of taste.",
        "c": "It enhances the efficiency of taste processing.",
        "d": "It allows for distinct coding of different tastes.",
        "e": "It improves the coordination between taste and smell.",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many possible smells can the thousand different odor receptors encode?",
        "a": "a quadrillion",
        "b": "a trillion",
        "c": "a quintillion",
        "d": "a billion",
        "e": "a million",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following sensations is NOT a component of somatosensation?",
        "a": "limb",
        "b": "touch",
        "c": "pain",
        "d": "taste",
        "e": "temperature",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which layer of the skin contains blood vessels, sweat glands, and hair follicles?",
        "a": "epidermis",
        "b": "subcutaneous tissue",
        "c": "dermis",
        "d": "stratum granulosum",
        "e": "hypodermis",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the fatty layer below the dermis?",
        "a": "papillary layer",
        "b": "reticular layer",
        "c": "squamous cell layer",
        "d": "subcutaneous layer",
        "e": "basal cell layer",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of mechanoreceptor transduces information about low-frequency vibration?",
        "a": "Meissner's corpuscles",
        "b": "Pacinian corpuscles",
        "c": "Merkel's disks",
        "d": "Ruffini's corpuscles",
        "e": "mechano-nociceptors",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are Merkel's discs most densely distributed in the body?",
        "a": "feet and toes",
        "b": "fingertips and lips",
        "c": "back and shoulders",
        "d": "elbows and knees",
        "e": "scalp and forehead",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "What triggers an action potential in mechanoreceptors?",
        "a": "temperature changes",
        "b": "chemical stimulation",
        "c": "electrical impulses",
        "d": "ligand binding",
        "e": "mechanical deformation",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mechanoreceptors have sharp and clearly defined receptive field borders?",
        "a": "Pacinian corpuscles",
        "b": "Merkel's discs",
        "c": "Ruffini's endings",
        "d": "mechano-nociceptors",
        "e": "Meissner's corpuscles",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two-point discrimination is the ability to",
        "a": "perceive depth and distance",
        "b": "discriminate between different textures",
        "c": "differentiate between closely spaced stimuli",
        "d": "sense pain and pressure",
        "e": "distinguish between hot and cold temperatures",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is two-point discrimination measured?",
        "a": "by observing muscle contractions",
        "b": "by applying pressure on adjacent points",
        "c": "by assessing visual acuity",
        "d": "by measuring the intensity of pain perception",
        "e": "by testing taste sensitivity",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "How are axons from receptors in the body carried to the brain?",
        "a": "by directly targeting the spinal cord",
        "b": "via the cranial nerves",
        "c": "via the spinal cord",
        "d": "by directly targeting the frontal cortex",
        "e": "by traveling through the limbs",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many cervical spinal segments are there?",
        "a": "ten",
        "b": "four",
        "c": "twelve",
        "d": "eight",
        "e": "six",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following reasons best explains why the spinal cord is segmented?",
        "a": "to enhance the spinal cord flexibility",
        "b": "to transmit signals through the skeletal system",
        "c": "to match the segmented skin organization",
        "d": "to protect the internal organs",
        "e": "to control muscle coordination",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a dermatome?",
        "a": "a segment of the spinal cord",
        "b": "a type of skin rash",
        "c": "a contagious skin condition",
        "d": "a dormant virus in the spinal cord",
        "e": "a pattern of skin innervation",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is there no C1 dermatome on the human skin?",
        "a": "The C1 segment has no sensory input.",
        "b": "The C1 segment is involved in motor output.",
        "c": "The C1 segment is affected by cranial nerve dysfunction.",
        "d": "The C1 segment is located in a different part of the body.",
        "e": "The C1 segment is responsible for a specific skin condition.",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why does the dermatome map appear distorted and confusing?",
        "a": "sensory overload",
        "b": "evolutionary changes",
        "c": "nerve damage",
        "d": "anatomical anomaly",
        "e": "genetic variations",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    }
]

